MAREIKE VAN WIE

DATA ANALYST

DETAILS

ADDRESS

Moving to Amsterdam currently in the United States

PHONE

(727) 710 9700

EMAIL

mareikevanwie@gmail.com

SKILLS

Microsoft Excel

SQL

Python

JavaScript

R

Machine Learning

Tableau

LINKS

Linkedin

<u>GitHub</u>

LANGUAGES

German

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ

PROFILE

Young- professional data analyst with an eye for details and willingness to learn. Looking for career opportunities in the field of data analytics. Passionate about the intersection of technology and democracy. Great social and team work skills with five years of community organizing experience.

Linkedin: https://linkedin.com/in/mareike-van-wie

GitHub: https://github.com/mvvanwie20

EXPERIENCE

Junior Data Analyst, Chargebacks911

Clearwater

Jun 2022 — Present

- · Automated fraud detection to make the department's output more efficient
- Created python scripts to find leakage between services and outcomes to streamline our reporting for clients
- Created complex SQL queries to collect data for daily and weekly business reports
- Developed a Python package for standardizing addresses to reduce the manual effort of report creation

Special Programs Coordinator, Public Ally at Dream in Green

Miami

Nov 2020 — Sep 2021

- Created visualizations and insights for reporting to help create a deeper understanding of Dream in Green's work and impact
- outlined the process plans and created market research as the backbone for the development of a waste recycling application
- · published articles for the Consortium for a Healthier Miami- Dade

EDUCATION

Data Analytics Certificate, University of Miami

Miami

Feb 2022 — Jul 2022

Courses include Python, R, SQL, Tableau, JavaScript, Machine Learning.

MA Digital Humanities, University of Groningen

Groningen

Sep 2019 — Jul 2021

Coursework included Python, SQL, Data and Society and Visualizing Data.

BA English Language and Culture, University of Groningen

Groningen

Sep 2016 — Jun 2019

Coursework included English Linguistics, Literature and Research Methods in Humanities. Presented thesis research at NASA's (Netherland's American Studies Association) annual conference.

PROJECTS

PyBer Analysis

https://github.com/mvvanwie20/PyE

Technologies used: Python, matplotlib, pandas

created data frames and visualizations for a ride-sharing company across rural, suburban and urban areas.

Movies-ETL

https://github.com/mvvanwie20/Mo

Technologies used: Python, pandas, numpy, sqlalchemy, psycopg2

Created an ETL function for movie data. Cleaned, merged and created a movie database.

COURSES

IBM Data Analytics, Coursera

Jul 2022 — Sep 2022

Humane Technology, Center for Humane Technology

Aug 2022 — Oct 2022